HERE Historical Files 6199/013
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
HERE Historical Files
1892-1989
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union (HERE)
6199/013
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Records.
6273167
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, February 22, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 22, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE), was a labor union for workers in the hospitality industry and was formed in 1891. HERE merged with the Union of Neddletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE), in 2004, to form UNITE HERE. HERE and later UNITE HERE were affiliated with the AFL-CIO until September of 2005, when the General Executive Board of UNITE HERE voted to leave the AFL-CIO and join in with the Change to Win Coalition.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6199 AV: HERE Audio-Visual Materials 6199 G: HERE Graphics 6199 MB: HERE Memorabilia 6199 mf: HERE Records on Microfilm 6199 PUBS: HERE Publications 6199/001: HERE Legislative Department Files 6199/002: HERE Western Region Local Files 6199/003: HERE Organizing Department Las Vegas Strike Files 6199/003 mf: HERE Organizing Department Files on Microfilm 6199/004: HERE Locals files 6199/004 mf: HERE Locals Files on Microfilm 6199/005: HERE Communications Department Files 6199/005 P: HERE Communications Department Photographs 6199/006: HERE General Executive Board Files 6199/006 mf: HERE General Executive Board Files on Microfilm 6199/007 mf: HERE Financial Records Files on Microfilm 6199/008 mf: HERE General President's Files on Microfilm 6199/009 mf: HERE General Secretary-Treasurer's Files on Microfilm 6199/010 mf: HERE General Office Legal Files on Microfilm 6199/011 mf: HERE Official Journals on Microfilm 6199/012 mf: HERE Joint Executive Board Files on Microfilm 6199/013 P: HERE Historical Photographs 6199/014: HERE Conventions Files 6199/015: HERE Editor Files
Hotels--Employees--Labor unions--United States; Restaurants--Employees--Labor unions--United States; Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union; Hotel, Hospital, Restaurant, and Tavern Employees' Union
6273167
- AFL. Labor Education., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Colorado Labor Peace Act, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ernst, Hugo. Files, 1923-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- HRE. Canadian Locals., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- HRE. Dining Car Employees, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- HRE. 1st General Convention. Proceedings., 1892 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- HRE. 4th General Convention. Proceedings., 1896 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- HRE. 8th General Convention. Proceedings., 1900 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- HRE. 9th General Convention. Proceedings., 1901 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- HRE. 10th General Convention. Proceedings., 1902 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- HRE. 12th General Convention. Proceedings., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- HRE. 21st General Convention. Proceedings., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- HRE. General Executive Board. Special Meeting., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- HRE. General Expenditures., 1898-1899 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- HRE. History. Croskey, R. E., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- HRE. History. Extracts from Journals. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- HRE. History. Extracts from the Official Journal. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- HRE. Ledger., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Local 20., 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Local 34., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Local 70. Kelly, John F., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Local 118. Charter., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Local 172. Re-Instatement., 1902 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Local 193. Charter., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Local 207. Minimum Wage Scale and Trade Regulations., 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Local 302. Cafeteria Call., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Local 550., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Monthly Report. August - November., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Restaurant Scale. Milwaukee., 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Sands, Charles E. Letter., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Trade Union Unity League., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Trademark Registration. Canada., 1902-1936 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Trademark Registration. States. California-Missouri., 1900-1911 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Trademark Registration. States. Nebraska-Wisconsin., 1901-1910 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Tademark Registration. U.S. Federal Government., 1901-1917 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Josephson, Matthew. Correspondence. Random House (folder 1), 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Josephson, Matthew. Correspondence. Random House (folder 2), 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Josephson, Matthew. Hutchinson, Joseph., 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Josephson, Matthew. Author. Biographical Essay., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Josephson, Matthew. Locals., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Josephson, Matthew. Miller, Ed S. Confidential Memorandum, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Josephson, Matthew. Miscellaneous., 1902-1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Josephson, Matthew. Sweet, Fred. Files., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Josephson, Matthew. Union House - Union Bar., 1953-1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)